By now, you've seen a
到现在为止 你已经见识了
(字幕整理：中国海洋大学 黄海广,haiguang2000@qq.com )
couple different learning algorithms, linear
几种不同的学习算法
regression and logistic regression.
包括线性回归和逻辑回归
They work well for many problems,
它们能够有效地解决许多问题
but when you apply them
但是当将它们应用到
to certain machine learning applications, they
某些特定的机器学习应用时
can run into a problem called
会遇到过度拟合(over-fitting)的问题
overfitting that can cause them to perform very poorly.
可能会导致它们效果很差
What I'd like to do in
在这段视频中
this video is explain to
我将为你解释
you what is this overfitting
什么是过度拟合问题
problem, and in the
并且
next few videos after this,
在此之后接下来的几个视频中
we'll talk about a technique called
我们将谈论一种
regularization, that will allow
称为正则化(regularization)的技术
us to ameliorate or to
它可以改善或者
reduce this overfitting problem and
减少过度拟合问题
get these learning algorithms to maybe work much better.
以使学习算法更好实现
So what is overfitting?
那么什么是过度拟合呢？
Let's keep using our running
让我们继续使用
example of predicting housing
那个用线性回归
prices with linear regression
来预测房价的例子
where we want to predict the
我们通过建立
price as a function of the size of the house.
以住房面积为自变量的函数来预测房价
One thing we could do is
我们可以
fit a linear function to
对该数据做线性回归
this data, and if we
如果这么做
do that, maybe we get
我们也许能够获得
that sort of straight line fit to the data.
拟合数据的这样一条直线
But this isn't a very good model.
但是 这不是一个很好的模型
Looking at the data, it seems
我们看看这些数据
pretty clear that as the
很明显
size of the housing increases, the
随着房子面积增大
housing prices plateau, or kind
住房价格的变化趋于稳定
of flattens out as we move to the right and so
或者越往右越平缓
this algorithm does not
因此该算法
fit the training and we
没有很好拟合训练数据
call this problem underfitting, and
我们把这个问题称为欠拟合(underfitting)
another term for this is
这个问题的另一个术语叫做
that this algorithm has high bias.
高偏差(bias)
Both of these roughly
这两种说法大致相似
mean that it's just not even fitting the training data very well.
意思是它只是没有很好地拟合训练数据
The term is kind of
这个词是
a historical or technical one,
过去传下来的一个专业名词
but the idea is that
它的意思是
if a fitting a straight line to
如果拟合一条直线
the data, then, it's as
到训练数据
if the algorithm has a
就好像算法
very strong preconception, or a
有一个很强的偏见
very strong bias that housing
或者说非常大的偏差
prices are going to vary
因为该算法认为房子价格与面积仅仅线性相关
linearly with their size and despite the data to the contrary.
尽管与该数据的事实相反
Despite the evidence of the
尽管相反的证据
contrary is preconceptions still
被事前定义为
are bias, still closes
偏差 它还是接近于
it to fit a straight line
拟合一条直线
and this ends up being a poor fit to the data.
而此法最终导致拟合数据效果很差
Now, in the middle, we could
我们现在可以在中间
fit a quadratic functions enter and,
加入一个二次项
with this data set, we fit the
在这组数据中
quadratic function, maybe, we get
我们用二次函数来拟合它
that kind of curve
然后可以拟合出一条曲线
and, that works pretty well.
事实证明这个拟合效果很好
And, at the other extreme, would be if we were to fit, say a fourth other polynomial to the data.
另一个极端情况是 如果我们拟合一个四次多项式
So, here we have five parameters,
因此在这里我们有五个参数
theta zero through theta four,
θ0到θ4
and, with that, we can actually fill a curve
这样我们可以拟合一条曲线
that process through all five of our training examples.
通过我们的五个训练样本
You might get a curve that looks like this.
你可以得到看上去如此的一条曲线
That, on the one
一方面
hand, seems to do
似乎
a very good job fitting the
对训练数据
training set and, that is
做了一个很好的拟合
processed through all of my data, at least.
因为这条曲线通过了所有的训练实例
But, this is still a very wiggly curve, right?
但是 这仍然是一条扭曲的曲线 对吧？
So, it's going up and down all
它不停上下波动
over the place, and, we don't actually
因此事实上
think that's such a good model for predicting housing prices.
我们并不认为它是一个预测房价的好模型
So, this problem we
所以 这个问题我们把他叫做
call overfitting, and, another
过度拟合或过拟合(overfitting)
term for this is that
另一个描述该问题的术语是
this algorithm has high variance..
高方差(variance)
The term high variance is another
高方差是另一个
historical or technical one.
历史上的叫法
But, the intuition is that,
但是 从第一印象上来说
if we're fitting such a high
如果我们拟合一个
order polynomial, then, the
高阶多项式 那么
hypothesis can fit, you know,
这个函数能很好的拟合训练集
it's almost as if it can
能拟合几乎所有的
fit almost any function and
训练数据
this face of possible hypothesis
这就面临可能函数太过庞大的问题
is just too large, it's too variable.
变量太多
And we don't have enough data
同时如果我们没有足够的数据
to constrain it to give
去约束这个变量过多的模型
us a good hypothesis so that's called overfitting.
那么这就是过度拟合
And in the middle, there isn't really
在两者之间的情况 叫"刚好合适"
a name but I'm just going to write, you know, just right.
这并不是一个真正的名词 我只是把它写在这里
Where a second degree polynomial, quadratic function
这个二次多项式 二次函数
seems to be just right for fitting this data.
可以说是恰好拟合这些数据
To recap a bit the
概括地说
problem of over fitting comes
过度拟合的问题
when if we have
将会在变量过多的时候
too many features, then to
发生
learn hypothesis may fit the training side very well.
这种时候训练出的方程总能很好的拟合训练数据
So, your cost function
所以 你的代价函数
may actually be very close
实际上可能非常接近于0
to zero or may be
或者
even zero exactly, but you
就是0
may then end up with a
但是
curve like this that, you
这样的曲线
know tries too hard to
它千方百计的拟合于训练数据
fit the training set, so that it
这样导致
even fails to generalize to
它无法泛化到
new examples and fails to
新的数据样本中
predict prices on new examples
以至于无法预测新样本价格
as well, and here the
在这里
term generalized refers to
术语"泛化"
how well a hypothesis applies even to new examples.
指的是一个假设模型能够应用到新样本的能力
That is to data to
新样本数据是
houses that it has not seen in the training set.
没有出现在训练集中的房子
On this slide, we looked at
在这张幻灯片上 我们看到了
over fitting for the case of linear regression.
线性回归情况下的过拟合
A similar thing can apply to logistic regression as well.
类似的方法同样可以应用到逻辑回归
Here is a logistic regression
这里是一个以x1与x2为变量的
example with two features X1 and x2.
逻辑回归
One thing we could do, is
我们可以做的就是
fit logistic regression with
用这样一个简单的假设模型
just a simple hypothesis like this,
来拟合逻辑回归
where, as usual, G is my sigmoid function.
和以前一样 字母g代表S型函数
And if you do that, you end up
如果这样做
with a hypothesis, trying to
你会得到一个假设模型
use, maybe, just a straight
这个假设模型是一条直线
line to separate the positive and the negative examples.
它直接分开了正样本和负样本
And this doesn't look like a very good fit to the hypothesis.
但这个模型并不能够很好的拟合数据
So, once again, this
因此
is an example of underfitting
这又是一个欠拟合的例子
or of the hypothesis having high bias.
或者说假设模型具有高偏差
In contrast, if you were
相比之下 如果
to add to your features
如果再加入一些变量
these quadratic terms, then,
比如这些二次项
you could get a decision
那么你可以得到一个判定边界
boundary that might look more like this.
像这样
And, you know, that's a pretty good fit to the data.
这样就很好的拟合了数据
Probably, about as
这很可能
good as we could get, on this training set.
是训练集的最好拟合结果
And, finally, at the other
最后
extreme, if you were to
在另一种极端情况下
fit a very high-order polynomial, if
如果你用高阶多项式来拟合数据
you were to generate lots of
你加入了很多
high-order polynomial terms of speeches,
高阶项
then, logistical regression may contort
那么逻辑回归可能发生自身扭曲
itself, may try really
它千方百计的
hard to find a
形成这样一个
decision boundary that fits
判定边界
your training data or go
来拟合你的训练数据
to great lengths to contort itself,
以至于成为一条扭曲的曲线
to fit every single training example well.
使其能够拟合每一个训练集中的样本
And, you know, if the
而且
features X1 and
如果x1和x2
X2 offer predicting, maybe,
能够预测
the cancer to the,
癌症
you know, cancer is a malignant, benign breast tumors.
你知道 癌症是一种恶性肿瘤 同时肿瘤也可能是良性
This doesn't, this really doesn't
确实
look like a very good hypothesis, for making predictions.
这个假设模型不是一个很好的预测
And so, once again, this is
因此
an instance of overfitting
这又是一个过拟合例子
and, of a hypothesis having
是一个
high variance and not really,
有高方差的假设模型
and, being unlikely to generalize well to new examples.
并且不能够很好泛化到新样本
Later, in this course, when we
在今后课程中
talk about debugging and diagnosing
我们会讲到调试和诊断
things that can go wrong with
诊断出导致学习算法故障的东西
learning algorithms, we'll give you
我们告诉你如何用
specific tools to recognize
专门的工具来识别
when overfitting and, also,
过拟合
when underfitting may be occurring.
和可能发生的欠拟合
But, for now, lets talk about
但是 现在 让我们谈谈
the problem of, if we
过拟合
think overfitting is occurring,
的问题
what can we do to address it?
我们怎么样解决呢
In the previous examples, we had
在前面的例子中
one or two dimensional data so,
当我们使用一维或二维数据时
we could just plot the hypothesis and see what was going
我们可以通过绘出假设模型的图像来研究问题所在
on and select the appropriate degree polynomial.
再选择合适的多项式来拟合数据
So, earlier for the housing
因此 以之前的房屋价格为例
prices example, we could just
我们可以
plot the hypothesis and, you
绘制假设模型的图像
know, maybe see that it
就能看到
was fitting the sort of
模型的曲线
very wiggly function that goes all over the place to predict housing prices.
非常扭曲并通过所有样本房价
And we could then use figures
我们可以通过绘制这样的图形
like these to select an appropriate degree polynomial.
来选择合适的多项式阶次
So plotting the hypothesis, could
因此绘制假设模型曲线
be one way to try to
可以作为决定多项式阶次
decide what degree polynomial to use.
的一种方法
But that doesn't always work.
但是这并不是总是有用的
And, in fact more often we
而且事实上更多的时候我们
may have learning problems that where we just have a lot of features.
会遇到有很多变量的假设模型
And there is not
并且
just a matter of selecting what degree polynomial.
这不仅仅是选择多项式阶次的问题
And, in fact, when we
事实上 当我们
have so many features, it also
有这么多的特征变量
becomes much harder to plot
这也使得绘图变得更难
the data and it becomes
并且
much harder to visualize it,
更难使其可视化
to decide what features to keep or not.
因此并不能通过这种方法决定保留哪些特征变量
So concretely, if we're trying
具体地说 如果我们试图
predict housing prices sometimes we can just have a lot of different features.
预测房价 同时又拥有这么多特征变量
And all of these features seem, you know, maybe they seem kind of useful.
这些变量看上去都很有用
But, if we have a
但是 如果我们有
lot of features, and, very little
过多的变量 同时
training data, then, over
只有非常少的训练数据
fitting can become a problem.
就会出现过度拟合的问题
In order to address over
为了解决过度拟合
fitting, there are two
有两个办法
main options for things that we can do.
来解决问题
The first option is, to try
第一个办法是要尽量
to reduce the number of features.
减少选取变量的数量
Concretely, one thing we
具体而言
could do is manually look through
我们可以人工检查
the list of features, and, use
变量的条目
that to try to decide which
并以此决定哪些变量更为重要
are the more important features, and, therefore,
然后
which are the features we should
决定保留哪些特征变量
keep, and, which are the features we should throw out.
哪些应该舍弃
Later in this course, where also
在今后的课程中
talk about model selection algorithms.
我们会提到模型选择算法
Which are algorithms for automatically
这种算法是为了自动选择
deciding which features
采用哪些特征变量
to keep and, which features to throw out.
自动舍弃不需要的变量
This idea of reducing the
这种减少特征变量
number of features can work
的做法是非常有效的
well, and, can reduce over fitting.
并且可以减少过拟合的发生
And, when we talk about model
当我们今后讲到模型选择时
selection, we'll go into this in much greater depth.
我们将深入探讨这个问题
But, the disadvantage is that, by
但是其缺点是
throwing away some of the
舍弃一部分特征变量
features, is also throwing
你也舍弃了
away some of the information you have about the problem.
问题中的一些信息
For example, maybe, all of
例如 也许所有的
those features are actually useful
特征变量
for predicting the price of a
对于预测房价都是有用的
house, so, maybe, we don't actually
我们实际上并不想
want to throw some of
舍弃一些信息
our information or throw some of our features away.
或者舍弃这些特征变量
The second option, which we'll
第二个选择
talk about in the
我们将在接下来的视频中讨论
next few videos, is regularization.
就是正则化
Here, we're going to keep
正则化中我们将保留
all the features, but we're
所有的特征变量
going to reduce the magnitude
但是数量级
or the values of the parameters
或参数数值的大小
theta J. And, this
θ(j)
method works well, we'll see,
这个方法非常有效
when we have a lot of
当我们有很多特征变量时
features, each of which contributes
其中每一个变量
a little bit to predicting
都能对预测产生一点影响
the value of Y, like we
y的值
saw in the housing price prediction example.
正如我们在房价的例子中看到的那样
Where we could have a lot
在那里我们可以有很多特征变量
of features, each of which
其中每一个变量
are, you know, somewhat useful, so, maybe, we don't want to throw them away.
都是有用的 因此我们不希望把它们删掉
So, this subscribes the
这就导致了
idea of regularization at a very high level.
正则化概念的发生
And, I realize that, all
我知道
of these details probably don't make sense to you yet.
这些东西你们现在可能还听不懂
But, in the next video, we'll
但是在接下来的视频中
start to formulate exactly how
我们将开始详细讲述
to apply regularization and, exactly what regularization means.
怎样应用正则化和什么叫做正则化均值
And, then we'll start to
然后我们将开始
figure out, how to use this,
讲解怎样使用正则化
to make how learning algorithms work
怎样使学习算法正常工作
well and avoid overfitting.
并避免过拟合